Clarisa Leu-Rodriguez

clarisaleu@gmail.com | 206-661-2804 https://clarisaleu.github.io | https://www.linkedin.com/in/clarisaleu/

OBJECTIVE

Experienced Software Engineer embarking on a new chapter, transitioning into Data Analytics with a goal of finding a role where I can merge my technical skills and problem-solving prowess, and passion for driving business-driven decisions.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING Grad. June 2021 | Seattle, WA

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN
APPLIED & COMPUTATIONAL
MATHEMATICAL SCIENCES
(FOCUS: DISCRETE MATHEMATICS
AND ALGORITHMS)
Grad. June 2021 | Seattle, WA

COURSEWORK

Discrete Mathematical Modeling
Linear Programming
Discrete Optimization
Combinatorial Theory
Continuous Mathematical Modeling
Applied Linear Algebra
Numerical Analysis
Statistics & Probability
Data Structures & Algorithms
Programming Languages
Databases & Database Languages
Theory of Computation

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Python • SQL • Matlab • Kotlin Java • PHP • R • C/C++ • Android

SOFTWARE

Jupyter Notebook • Excel • MySQL RStudio • Android Studio • VSCode

SKILLS

Project Management • Software Implementation • Data Analysis Research • Effective Communication Quick Learner • Task Organization Time Management

EXPERIENCE

Experienced Software Engineer embarking META | SOFTWARE ENGINEER, WEARABLE EXPERIENCES

August 2021 - November 2023 | Seattle, Washington

- Participated in the development of key features within wearable device application, contributing to user engagement and usability which received positive feedback and contributed to team accomplishments.
- Actively engaged in the planning and coordination of development sprints
 quarterly for team goals, ensuring that milestones were met according to plandemonstrating the ability to organize tasks and collaborate with engineers,
 project managers, and designers effectively.
- Collaborated with experienced engineers on the implementation of critical performance enhancements, improving app responsiveness and quality on wearable devices.
- Built strong foundation in Android software development and an understanding of wearable device ecosystems while working alongside experienced professionals in the field.

FACEBOOK | SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, GAMING EXPERIENCES June 2020 – September 2020 | Seattle, Washington

- Successfully implemented and shipped the new gaming clips browsing surface for the FB Mobile Application, enhancing the discoverability of gaming content on both the FB Gaming App and FB Games Tab in Hack / PHP.
- Actively participated in code reviews and received positive feedback for code quality and adherence to best practices.
- Actively participated in testing, debugging, and performance optimization, ensuring a polished and reliable application for users.
- Maintained thorough project documentation, facilitating knowledge transfer and supporting future development efforts.

FACEBOOK | FBU FOR ENGINEERING INTERN, ANDROID DEVELOPMENT June 2019 – September 2019 | Seattle, Washington

- Collaborated with two other FBU interns to design and develop a travel application using Android, from ideation to execution showcasing effective teamwork and an innovative approach to helping people remember where they have traveled and encouraging people to travel more.
- Contributed to the design of an intuitive user interface, enhancing the overall user experience of the travel application and receiving positive feedback during user testing.

UW MEDICAL CENTER | RESEARCH ASSISTANT, RADIATION ONCOLOGY November 2018 – June 2019 | Seattle, Washington

- Contributed to the development of a novel physical compensator-based IMRT device, paving the way for more affordable and advanced Radiation Therapy solutions to address global health disparities.
- Assisted in a software implementation and data analyst role in research project that was featured in The Physics World's "Top 10 Breakthroughs of 2018," underscoring the significance and impact of our work.
- Developed a Python script that integrated with RayStation, enhancing the precision and efficiency of Radiation Therapy planning and delivery.
- Played a key role in the collection, analysis, and presentation of data in Python and MATLAB, enabling the research team to make informed decisions and advance the project.